This is not, they don't know anything about it.
Well, there are some pretty dramatic cases
that were studied also by OSAP
that were written up into reports.
All they have to do is ask for it.
Congress seemed to only know a little bits and pieces.
They were unaware, seemingly unaware
that OSAP ever existed.
When the Navy guys were asked,
is there anything between Project,
Blue Book and A-Tip?
Nope.
Well, that's not true.
I mean, you know, it was a lot of money.
Millions of public dollars were spent on that.
The stories have been all over the world.
The book has been written of the people
who are involved in the program
of Comfort and talked about it.
How can they not know?
Yeah, no.
Yeah, ma'am.
So I guess, you know, kind of where we're at here
is it would be really great to hear from somebody
who actually worked in these programs.
And I think we're going to get that pretty soon.
Thanks for kind of telling us about the report
and getting to the point we're at.
I guess where I'm at is I'm just excited
to see kind of how this is all assimilated
into our processes like so that I want the American public
to know if this is true.
I, you know, I don't have the luxury of disbelief
on certain things, but I want it to be stated
and boldly stated, I don't know,
when that's going to come and what the truth is
or what the full truth is, but I think we're getting closer.
Well, the public also needs to understand
as OSAP came to realize that this is way beyond just UFOs.
You're never going to solve this mystery
just by studying lights in the sky
or craft that appear on the sensor
and you can't see with your own eyes.
You have to look at the big picture.
And unfortunately, a lot of that gets really weird.
So strange, maybe it's almost by design.
That it's so strange that people are reluctant to dig into it.
That's how many in the Pentagon seemingly reacted
to the reports that came in from OSAP,
from the Big Low Organization, it gets really strange.
The stuff that skinwalker is really strange.
It's easy to make fun of.
It's easy to dismiss because it's so strange,
but it really did happen.
And the reports that have not yet been made public
lay it out in very specific detail
and we're going to be getting into that more
in the course of the next few months on this program.
Absolutely.
And I just want to kind of testify here
that I think I'm nuts and bolts.
My family thinks I'm just fucking nuts, but the thing is
that I have a resistance.
I have a resistance to the high strangers,
to the weirdness, to the things that seem
to happen around the UFO phenomenon.
I am cool with Bob Lazar's description of craft,
as an example.
That's what initially the science of that, how that would work.
I am cool with the nuts and bolts.
I get an allergy when it comes to the weirder stuff.
And you know, that's why even with everything I know
that have seen and been briefed on, I have an allergy to it.
So I can understand the public kind of trying to be like,
that's too weird to be true.
We can accept flying saucers.
We can accept UFOs.
We can accept reverse engineering and governments
hiding this and there being a cover up to some degree.
We can accept that.
But when it gets weirder, I empathize with the resistance to it.
Now, I'm going to try.
I'm going to try to look at straight and say,
look at it, just like I would anything else.
But I think hearing from people directly
who have direct experiences in these programs,
that's going to be the key to understanding that.
Well, Dr. James LeCatsky has spent 20 years
as a rocket scientist at the DIA.
That's as nuts and bolts as you get, studying rockets,
our rockets, other nation's rockets, potential threats.
Jay Stratton, his friend and colleague, also at the DIA,
nuts and bolts guy, reverse engineering,
how to figure out technology, figuring out the nature of threats,
of all sorts, both nuts and bolts people,
who came to understand that this mystery
goes way beyond nuts and bolts.
Jay Stratton, we've heard from him today
in pieces of the conversation that you and I had with him.
What we haven't heard is some of his personal experiences
and that goes way beyond just studying lights in the sky.
And hopefully, sometime in the course of 2023,
he's going to open up about that.
Yeah, well, look, man, I'm looking forward to it.
As always, I'm willing to learn
and the main thing is, I think that having those direct
conversations are going to help around the corners
for a lot of people, including myself.
So anyway, thanks, man, that would be fun.
Yeah, all right.
Yeah.
Follow him as to the weaponized,
the presentation of Jeremy Corball,
George Nap, Dark Horse Entertainment,
and cadence 13 studios available now for free
on the Odyssey app wherever you get your shows.