In 2018, I released through Kayleus and Mystery Wire a 13-page report about the Tic-Tac incident.
Tic-Tac occurred in 2004.
Your friend, Commander Dave Fraver, is the aviator for the Navy that had the direct encounter
with this strange object five years later when Ossap is born.
The first case they start looking at is Tic-Tac.
And the person they came to rely on to write the first report and investigate a report
on Tic-Tac was Jay Stratton.
I released that report in 2018.
It had no insignion, it wasn't signed, it doesn't say who wrote it.
But we could say now, he's the guy wrote it.
And it was great work.
He talked to all these aviators and different people who were involved in it.
It is one report that then became a much bigger report that has not been made public,
but eventually will be someday.
So that's one bit of work that he did.
A second thing that the public would know about is the durds.
There are 38 of these durds, defense intelligence referenced documents, that's the acronym
what it means.
And 38 of those reports were prepared for the Ossap program and as Jay explained to us
when we met with them, you know, it was meant to be a baseline to establish what our baseline
is for a science and technology in specific kinds of categories and to project what it might
be 50 years from now.
You know, I remember when I made some of those, when you and I release some of those reports,
people were gripping and moaning, all this is sci-fi, it's nonsense, it's garbage science.
Well, it's not, that's not how it was received by the defense industry.
They love those reports because it works a really good work.
And they needed a baseline from which they could compare when they had UFO cases to analyze,
is this ours?
Could it be ours?
Could we duplicate that 50 years from now in the, in many times the answer
was no?
Right.
And Jay actually talked about this in this interview that we did, it's like he was saying,
look, we were trying to find the disruptive technologies in 50 years from now.
The things that we were seeing, the things that we're going on, we didn't have good
explanations for.
So we have to theorize and get out there like what could it be, how could it be happening?
It's so interesting to me the way he also said he was so dismissive in a, in a, in a
calm, cool, collected way because he really empathizes with people to have less information
than him.
And I get that.
So certain things that are classified within our department of defense, he can't just
like go out on Twitter and say, even if he gets on Twitter, you know what I mean?
But he was very clear that if something was identifiable, if something was ours, if something
was a traditional object or a known foreign nation, or even a question that could be a
foreign nation that a known, despite the capabilities, that those would not be included
in his reporting, in his analysis.
And he really specifically said, you know, I get it that people think it's just one piece
of evidence like just a video, but you and I are hyper personally aware that there's other
corroborative evidence that is not for public consumption.
Jason said himself that we had more information.
And so when you say, oh, it's, you know, birds, balloons, optical illusions, reflections,
pilot error.
He's like bullshit.
It's not.
We would never have included it.
And it's nice to hear him say that because it carries a lot more weight than just, you
know, it actually supports the pilots and people that know because they were there.
Exactly.
I mean, you know, the, the armchair experts, the debunkers on social media just throw anything
out.
And see what sticks against the wall.
It's birds.
It's, you know, it's exhaust from a jet.
It's ridiculous is what it is.
And, you know, for that explanation to work, any of those, you have to assume the U.S.
military are idiots, that the pilots are idiots, that people, manning the sensors are idiots,
that the analysis done by intelligence officials afterward, that they're all idiots, that
they don't recognize a bird from, you know, an unknown object traveling at a high rate of
speed.
Jay did share with us that there is so much information that cannot be shared with the public
for national security reasons, that went into their analyses of these key cases, gimbal,
tick-tack, go fast, and a lot of others that you and I got into.
So he worked with OSAP with Bigelow and Colum and Lakatski and any developed relationships
and other parts of the Pentagon and the intelligence community that served him well years
later.
These seven months after OSAP starts, it ended.
And then Luelizando comes along, picks up the pieces, creates what came to be known
as a tip, and Jay was directly involved with that.
Well, I don't also Jay developed, it was so cool hearing him talk about this.
He developed what he said was like asymmetrical approaches, so he would get people in different
fields because they had different ways to solve problems and he would get them with their
specialties like a biologist that would look at the spread of information a little bit differently.
So I really appreciated the way that he would take an intelligence approach to problems
that haven't been solved in traditional means.
So my point is he actually developed staff and teams and this was a big deal.
I think that what he did in developing, and for people that don't know, so OSAP, we keep
saying that, it's a barrier to repeat advanced aerospace weapon systems application program.
That was the largest, best funded government, DIA UFO program in history that is publicly known.
And then as that transition, it turned into a tip, advanced aerospace threat identification
program.
So those are the acronyms that we keep talking about, but I think it's important to show
that there's individuals and intelligence agencies that are taking this seriously and building
infrastructure for better reporting and want to be transparent with the American public,
to the degree that is safe with, you know, with problems, with foreign problems, that's so
encouraging.
I love that there are a multitude of agencies now that are developing beyond an interest,
but a process to help bring this information to where it needs to go.
It will make you and me obsolete, maybe it's journalists, but it's great, it's happening.
OSAP, the DIA program lasted 27 months and then, you know, because of it, it got into some
pretty controversial areas and became a hot potato within depending on intelligence community.
Louis Osando steps forward and was able to keep something going of a form of the program.
It's not as big, it's not as high profile, but he kept it going and was upset eventually that
it just didn't get enough attention. It didn't get enough resources to be able to do the work
they really needed. J, who was working with Lou, their good friends, a lot of mutual respect
between the two of them, moved on to another job. He was aware, as he told us, he was aware that
Louis Osando was going to leave and the reasons why he was going to leave was upset. He was not
aware that the New York Times story was going to come and then boom and happens one day.
So that's a funny thing. So Lou, I mean, really, people just don't get this, but Lou is a champion.
I mean, he took something and he kept it going and he made it strong and, you know, I think
and I think J really appreciates that. You can tell from the conversations.
So we get to the point where J is now out of the UFO topic, that's not his task with his intelligence
job, so he's doing something else. And the way he said it to us was so cool is on December 17th,
you know, whatever it was, 2017 when the New York Times thing, somebody put a paper bang right on his
desk and says, you know, Merry Christmas or have a birthday one of these said, we'll let him tell that story.
I knew Lou was leaving. So again, at that point in the 2017 day and to early 18th time frame,
I was in a job that UFOs were not on my job, and any former fashion. So I did not do that job.
Very conscious throughout my career sticking to what I'm paid to do, right?
However, again, Lou and I are friends and the folks that kind of took it over when I left,
I knew him all. And you know, I got a face to face, it's called a tampered, it's a kind of face
time with Lou and his office. And this was about, I think, three or so days before he dropped his letter
and he's holding his letter. You know, there's something that effect, things like,
you know, here's what I'm doing. And I said, you know, good luck. And then, you know, loan behold,
he's on stage with, with how and, and Steve Justice and the team there, and I'm watching.
And it's still at this point. I had no idea it will be back in, in this topic at all, right?
I'm watching as an outsider, just like everybody, but I could actually text Lou if I wanted, right?
So I had some insider, but I'm watching and, and interested.
Are you sympathetic to his stated reasons for leaving it that he was frustrated that I can't get through
to the Secretary of Defense and Trump, but this and it needs to be a higher priority?
I am. You know, what we needed was, was a recognized program of record as we call it, right?
We needed something that had the, the umph behind it, the power behind it, the authority behind it,
to do a lot of things in order to get the answers that needed to be, the answers we needed. And
you know, I was building towards that later.