Imagine being 12 years old, already having 30 bone fractures, and wondering, why can't I just play like other kids?
I'm Leanne, and I was diagnosed with brittle bone disease.
Now, I'm running the Bank of America as Chicago Marathon for Larry Children's.
So, every kid can just be a kid.
Join Bank of America in supporting Leanne's cause, give it to can at baveta.com slash support Leanne.
What would you like the powers to do, Bank of America?
References to charitable organizations is not endorsement by Bank of America Corporation.
Every minute your finance team spends wrestling with data is a minute lost.
Insight software's AI powered insights instantly move you from complexity to clarity.
Automated analysis, real-time reporting, strategic recommendations, all at your fingertips.
Transform how your finance team works and watch your business grow.
Stop wasting time, start making smarter decisions.
Learn more at insightsoftware.com slash AI.
Secrets, cover ups, and strange phenomena.
UFOs and ideas that challenge reality itself.
All these mysteries, all this time, we're ever going to get to the bottom of these.
My name is George Nap, I dig into new stories that others can't or won't.
I'm Jeremy Corbel, and for some reason, people tell me things they probably shouldn't.
And this is weapon weapons.
We're back, we'll tell you mine.
Oh my gosh, so much, man.
Well, I guess we should start with a number of weeks ago, the new anticipated UFO report.
Official UFO report came out from the government, and there's been a lot of reactions from, you know,
dismissals in opinion articles in the New York Times to other people that got it right.
But this was anticipated.
We're supposed to come out on Halloween, right?
Twenty-twenty-two.
Here we are on twenty-twenty-three now.
And finally, it's out.
But.
So they call it the twenty-twenty-two annual report on UAP, unidentified aerial phenomena.
It's actually the twenty-twenty-three report since it did not come out in twenty-twenty-two.
And looking at it, you know, the first impression you get is,
nobody's going to wrench their backpick in this thing up.
It's only a couple of pages.
They got a title page, and then a table of contents page, and a couple of index pages at the back,
and terminology, not much report here.
I'm reminded of, remember when light beer first came out, the slogan was,
tastes great, less filling.
That's what comes to mind for this.
Yeah, in defense of the depth of the report, it is a report of a classified report.
It's a report that they did a classified report.
But there are some really sneaky things that you brought to my attention that we're kind of done in this.
And I'd like kind of people to know about this from a new standpoint.
Well, you know, I think there's a difference between this report and the one that came out in twenty-twenty-one.
The UAP task force report to Congress.
It had a hundred and forty-four cases.
It's at a hundred and forty-three.
We're unidentified.
This one has a lot more cases.
They added, it's a five hundred and ten cases.
So there's the goods news is that the reporting system that has been implemented is working.
They even got reports from the U.S. Air Force that says in here, and the U.S. Navy primarily.
We don't know where these incidents happen.
There's almost no detail whatsoever.
We don't know if they were in space, whether they were under sea, whether they're over U.S. air space,
or the military encountered them somewhere on the world.
Don't know what the size or shape or capabilities of these are.
We know that there's indication that at least some of these cases are advanced technology that had capabilities
that were really intriguing.
But really, no details at all.
I think the UFO public was prepared to be underwhelmed.
Maybe not quite this underwhelmed.
But I mean, overall, there's some good stuff.
The fact that they reported it at all, that they're getting better at identifying what's truly unidentified
and anomalous on what isn't, is pretty good.
But we know that this is all domain.
We know that these cases span from space air to sea.
Now, that's not something obviously that's put out to the public.
But that's why it's called all domain.
That's why it's called Transmedium.
So I think people got this title based on their bias, like wrong.
I think the titles right in the report.
There's a top of it.
I think page five can we read that and want people to hear what they said.
You know, continued reporting and robust analysis are providing better fidelity on UAP events.
But many cases remain unresolved.
That's right in the report.
That's the headline.
That is the important part.
And then people try to cherry pick and say, all this stuff that we know is false.
And they put it through major publications.
You know, the mass media needs to look and read everything to be informed.
It doesn't always happen.
It seems like there was a concerted effort to water it down.
I mean, this is the most exciting topic in the world.
It's the biggest question in human existence in the history of civilization.
Are we alone?
It would change the world of what's we get a confirmation that there's another intelligent somewhere.
They're out there or living among us here.
It's huge.
And they do their best to add this bureaucratic jingo type language that
junk it up and to dilute how interesting it really is to to make it as least interesting as possible.
It seemed like in the terms that they use.
And you also think about like, you know, who are they that are doing this?
If you just look at who writes certain types of articles, you get a sense that they're,
this is not reporting.
These are people that are inserting certain types of topographical, you know, premises that they come up with.
They come up with biases they come up with.
So if we just report the news, the line, I just read, that's the news.
That's what's important.
So look, I don't know what UFOs are.
I don't.
But I know that it's unexplained and that there's a mechanical aspect too.
Well, they made a point of adding in a bunch of cases that I think were taken out of the original report.
They said in the...
Think of you know.
Well, it says that they added in a hundred and some cases that had been left out.
So adding these back in increased the total.
But it allowed them to say, oh gosh, heck a lot of these are balloons.
A heck a lot of these are drones.
A lot of it is trash, which is, you remember the New York Times had this pre-bunking piece,
where they predicted that's what this report is going to show.
It's a bunch of drones, it's a bunch of balloons.
Yes, drones exist.
We're aware that birds fly in the sky.
That's not anything new.
I mean, UFOs 101, you learn that 90 to 95% of all UFO cases are explainable.
If you get enough information, they're explainable.
They are drones, they're balloons, they're planets, they're clouds, things that sort.
That is the starting point for this conversation.
We're aware that cases can be explained.
We're also aware that while 90% are explainable,
9 out of 10 are not reported at all.
Hold on, it just back up.
I'm fucking record scratch.
Okay.
They excluded a bunch of cases because they were explainable,
so let's now work on the ones that are not.
What you're saying is they brought those cases back into
be able to give these statistics.
Yeah, it says it.
The ODI preliminary assessment discussed 144 UAP reports
and had an information cut off date of five March 2021.
Since then, arrows received 247 new UAP reports,
but an additional 119 UAP reports on events that occurred
before March 5th, 2021.
But we're not included in that assessment
have been discovered or reported.
So they took them that have been discarded and put them back in
and allows them to sort of dilute the overall impact of this.
By saying, oh gosh, these are explainable.
And we know who discarded them.
So they could focus on the true UAP mystery.
And this was a slide of hand.
Is that what you're saying?
Oh, it's a little deceptive, I think.
You know, by adding those back in that they already know
or explainable.
The reason they were kicked out is because they're explainable.
Is it fair to say that there's a minimization process
that's occurring to the public?
They're trying to minimize some of the gravity of this
to the public.
Is that fair to say?
Well, they brought back in cases that are explainable.
They dumb down the language.
Made it as clunky as possible.
And as least interesting as possible.
Trying to make it less dramatic.
Almost as if hey, there's really nothing to see here, folks.
We did our duty.
We got this report.
We now have processes in place that
where it makes it easier to report this stuff.
But we're explaining it.
Don't you worry you're pretty little heads kind of thing.
And one of the reasons we know about that process for the
first report is because you and I were able to talk to
the chief scientist for the UAP task force.
That's right.
And he's a guy who is well-known to our listeners,
to viewers from television.
Dr. Travis Taylor has been on ancient aliens number
of times.
He's been on the Secret of Skinwalker Ranch at the past couple of years.
A well-known as a scientist who is interested in the UFO
and related mysteries.
What most people don't know is that he was serving
as the chief scientist for the UAP task force.
We learned that and we're floored by it on a trip.
We made two Alabama last last fall, a last summer.
I learned about it before, but you reported on it first.
You told people about that.
And it kind of threw people for a loop because they know
from TV, you know from this.
But look, this guy's a serious scientist.
And he's done a lot of work.
And he was sp...