typically brought in and tasked because he had certain skill sets that would be good for this
job. And we know who brought him in and it's so interesting man. I want to get to something
we had this crazy trip. You want to start talking about that? Yeah. All right. For anybody that
doesn't know mine and George's friendship and working together once in a while, I get some
call from George and it's like pack your bags. We got to go get films. We're doing an interview.
And you know just immediately I know oh gosh, so this is the thing now. So my perspective,
I've actually never told you this. My perspective was, okay, George has hopefully a really important
interview to hear from somebody that could shed light to the American public who's never gone
on camera. And this is kind of the background. You kind of gave me, you know, this could happen.
But there's also an event going on before we get to that. I'm just like, okay, let me adjust my life
to like leave in a few days. I needed a second camera. I don't even know how to do
aperture right, you know, professional filmmaker. I don't even know how to do this stuff right.
I knew this is important. I was like, I need somebody. I called up my buddy Niles Harrison.
He's laying on the beach in Mexico, right, where he just bought a house. And I'm like,
I need you on a plane right now. Just, I need to get you to Vegas. And he's like, well, I got all my
stuff and we have to put it in storage. This dude, Niles Harrison dude, you're my idol man. He packed
everything up. And in two days, he landed in Vegas to meet us to be the DP or the backup for us. The
only guy could trust, you know? And I still don't know what the mission is. So I can't tell him
the mission, you know? So it's just like this fun kind of experience where I'm like, we get
to Vegas, I'm like, what's going on, you know, and we hop right on a flight. So just so you know,
I mean, it was, it was crazy man. This is how it works with you. And me is sometimes I call you
something as you call me. And it's time to go. Well, the premise for this, there were, there were
multiple reasons to make this trip. Huntsville, Alabama is a defense hub. A lot of interesting
defense contractors have grown up around there. Of course, it's Rocket City. It's where the,
it's where the birthplace of the U.S. base program really was, Warner Bond,
Brown and his team were all down there. I didn't even know where we were going. Yeah, you know,
you're now you're saying it, but like you said, you tell me, okay, let we're going to
Huntsville, my Huntsware and you're like Huntsville, I'm like, why? Well, in a sense, you know,
I hate to admit this, but Huntsville has become sort of the de facto UFO research capital of
America for a long time. For the past 30 years, it's been Las Vegas because of Robert
Bigelow, his needs organization that became bass that was headquarters for the Ossap program,
which that's a lot of acronyms, but that program was the largest UFO investigation ever funded
by the U.S. government that we know of. And so, because of Bigelow and Colin Keller her and their
colleagues in Las Vegas, Las Vegas was a hub for this research. I think Huntsville might now have
that title because of all the people who are concentrated there, the defense contractors that have
grown up around the U.S. rocket program, the U.S. Army's Redstone Arsenal is there. In addition to
the defense contractors and the rocket programs and a lot of government agencies,
there is also a UFO organization, SCU, the scientific coalition for UAP studies.
Headed by a guy named Rich Hoffman, he's put together a team of scientists. They've done some great
analyses on key cases. The Puerto Rico UFO that was looked like a transmedium for one thing
and they did a tech tech paper. They're doing some great work, but they have an annual conference.
I've been invited to go to each one of them and finally I wanted to go because
they only had a really great lineup of speakers, but I had a feeling that the audience might be
more interesting than the people who are up there on the dance given the speeches.
Does it ever feel like you're a marketing professional just speaking into the void?
But with LinkedIn ads, you can know you're reaching the right decision makers and network of
130 million of them, in fact. You can even target buyers by job title industry company,
seniority skills, and did I say job title? See how you can avoid the void and reach the
right buyers with LinkedIn ads. Spend $250 on your first campaign and get a free $250 credit for
the next one. Get started at LinkedIn.com slash campaign in terms and conditions apply.
The drip and satisfy your cravings. Bring home the drip with Velvita.
Okay, so to back up, so there is, you know, these UFO study groups, but this is one that really
focuses on the science and technology and it gets great speakers and members and we know
people just come into quietly silently listen that they might be interesting people because it's
in rocket city, but you had an idea that we were going to get a specific interview, but at this
point you're telling me, we're going to this conference, it's a UFO conference, I come on
George and you're like, no, no, it's a cool one. It's like science and I'm like, all right, I texted
it, uh, Ryan Graves, you know, the fighter pilot that everybody knows now and I just wanted to get
a beer with him because we had talked so much and so that was, I was like, okay, I'm coming with
me, we're Ryan, we're going to have a beer and that didn't end up happening. We ended up missing
each other two ships in the night, but we met a number of really interesting people and we're
able to get some first-ever interviews with people that we're going to come forward and also
recorded with and talked with individuals who people don't know yet, but are also critical and
essential to the UFO puzzle and what's going on with in government and Congress and different
intelligence agencies looking at this, I mean, just straight up, it was fascinating. We had fun,
and we're driving at a car, you think I'm going to kill us, you know, we're making jokes about green
pyramids. Our primary concern is getting their life, which is not a given, and the light of the fact
that Jeremy is the person driving. Yeah, the navigator. And the navigator, yeah.
Hopefully we arrive in one piece. Oh, fuck, there was a little work in guy with a goddamn pyramid.
It always had a pyramid or triangle, but that's just a drone. That's construction work. So that's
not a pyramid that you see right there. Well, it's a guy building a pyramid. Oh, yeah,
for the guy building, so is it like the government building a pyramid? Would that be accurate to say?
You could go in for that. I'm staying. I'm going to. And also record. I fucking drive.
Then we had a we had a lot of fun, but what happens next, George? I mean, this is a really neat moment for us.
So I had hoped that we'd be able to land this really important interview with someone who has never
spoken on camera before has never interacted with the media in a way where he could be quoted.
Someone I have known for a long time. You protected his name. I could never mention his name.
I, you know, I've known about him. And then I got to know him. I happen to know that he loves
Linda Mishua Khan, this Mexican restaurant in Las Vegas, and has been known to hang out there.
He's he's worked with the nids guys with Bigelow and Callahar and some of those folks.
We'll go into more detail on that in a moment. But there he is. We now know that he had relocated
to Huntsville. One of my favorite stories of last year that we produced for KLA S and Mystery
Wire was about this company. This defense contractor in Huntsville, Alabama that put out an amazing
seemingly innocuous release about two men they had hired. Actually there were two releases.
The one was an announcement that they had hired a guy named Jay Stratton who had been a
lifelong intelligence officer who had worked at the Pentagon in very high level positions for a
number of years. And I was astonished to see his name released in the public because it's been
forbidden that I could ever mention it. So that's the guy. That's the guy. Jay Stratton.
The world doesn't really know Jay Stratton. I mean, some people figured it out. There's been
little things now that have come out. But at that time you had kind of held back. So but the
quite the big question is who's Jay Stratton? Jay Stratton. So if anyone who's read the book
Skinwalkers at the Pentagon written with Dr. James LeCatsky and Colin Keller, there are references
to this guy in there. I don't want to use the name Jay Stratton. He used a different name, but
references to a high level guy, a really credible intelligence officer who was involved in a
key positions in these UFO programs. Ossap, A-tip, the UAP task force and arrow. He is the only
person who has involved in all of those who is sort of the common link from the start of Ossap
through the creation of arrow and continues, I think, to advise the folks who are involved with that.
There's only one guy that's been there for that whole trip who has worked with Ossap and then
Luel as under with A-tip and created, in essence, the UAP task force who got the government
to ship from using the term UFO to UAP who's work. We'll talk about some examples of it.
Back up, you just said, Jay Stratton, did you just say Jay Stratton created the UAP task
force? Yeah. Okay, so that would explain to me why Numerous-