For us, military, act of military individuals were so stoked to see J. Stratton's name come
out.
And I said, why?
And they're like, because this is the one individual who is credible military intelligence,
who's where DIA, who's working tons of programs in ONI, all these different intelligence agencies
that has pushed not only to be honest and true to the American public, but to create
an interface so that we could honestly bring forward to the American public what we know
and don't know about the UFO or what he helped systematized UAP process.
And the reason he said he did that was to destigmatize reporting of UFOs.
So this guy is trying to destigmatize reporting of UFOs, trying to systematize it.
So that reporting becomes better as a learning process as bumpy as it is.
People would put reports in from let's say the nimmits or any of these encounters.
They wouldn't hear back.
They thought it got lost in the ether.
They didn't want to get mental checks.
But he made it cool to report and learned along the way.
I respect that.
So a lot of military people are like, that is so amazing to get him to talk because he's
talking for us.
We don't have voices.
He's got a voice for us.
So I just want to tell you that's what I've gotten a lot of.
So that's who we're talking about.
Talking about a very serious, credible individual who's worked in intelligence capacity,
who's done the right thing and he's done the right thing in a way to help destigmatize
and communicate with the American public.
So we don't have the same problems as Project Bluebook, the cover what's in his own words.
What Roswell did to the situation, the lies from our government.
I think it's, so now I know we might be interviewing this guy and that's really cool.
Well, I learned that he was going to be there, that he and his colleague Travis Taylor
were going to be at this event, this SCU conference.
They're going to be in the audience.
It was sort of the coming out party in a sense.
Both had been hired to work by Radiance Technologies and the releases when they were
each of them was hired.
Jay was hired first and then he convinced Radiance that, hey, Travis Taylor is a really qualified
guy.
He's the guy I'd like to work with here and they hired him as well.
And the releases for both of those guys were astonishing in that unlike most defense contractors,
they don't want to talk about UFOs.
I don't want to mention it.
They don't want to give it any credence, even some of them who probably have a deeper
roots with the topic than they cared to admit, they don't highlight it.
This Radiance Technology, those releases both bragged about, in essence, they highlighted
the fact that both these guys had worked on UFO programs for the US government.
It was as if they were saying, this is no longer a forbidden topic.
We want to be involved in it at every level.
In fact, if you got some UFO contracts to give out to private industry, we're ready
to go.
I think I can get away with saying this.
I think it's fine, but so we filmed that Radiance, that's okay.
You did a news report, how cool to be shown what we were able to be shown.
We couldn't film what they're doing there.
To some degree, I mean, obviously they have offices at Wright Patterson for their technology
company.
But with what they could show us, we had to get the special badges which we couldn't even
photograph.
All that stuff.
Do you remember when I was pushing him, I was like, that's a skiff.
Let me see inside the skiff.
I don't believe it.
I don't do that to everybody.
He's not going to show you.
And then they're finally like, okay, you can peek inside the door, but they don't say
a word.
There's something going on in there.
But it's okay.
It's okay.
I think I can, yeah.
I didn't believe him opened that door.
Holy cow.
I mean, there was some cool stuff going on.
Bam, close the door.
It was nice to them to let me peek and just to verify, you know what?
It's a cool company.
It's a lot of ways.
It's owned by the employees.
The employees own.
Everybody benefits from if they, when they do well.
They have offices in 17 states, nearly all of them are attached to or within US Air Force
bases.
So they're at Wright Patterson.
They're at Nellus, two bases that we know have a long history of involvement with the
subject that is near and dear to our heart.
And so they do serious work.
You can see hints of it on their website.
The kind of things they do.
But essentially, that company does reverse engineering work, which in the UFO world, that
term is laden with, with hidden meaning, you know, it suggests taking things apart to
figure out how they work, things that we did not build.
But they do that.
And Jay Stratton, who went to work for him, specialized in reverse engineering.
And not just technology, not just systems, machinery, but in situations.
When he worked for the DIA, he would reverse engineer potential threats, figure out who might
be flying what their capabilities were and what kind of systems we might need to
counter that.
I mean, he was, he was a top expert in that kind of work.
And we'll allow him to maybe explain some of the jobs that he held at the Pentagon.
Definitely.
And additionally, you know, I also want to be clear, we weren't shown anything we weren't
supposed to see.
But it was just neat that we got that tour and be able to see in certain rooms.
Obviously, they keep a real kind of locking key.
But I just got to say it was such a cool experience for a company like that to be so open
for the first time with journalists coming in there and even the President sat down and did
an interview and you did a report on it.
It really shows that they're interest in the reverse engineering and things.
I'm sure they would love to have some of the goodies.
And they would be great company.
Well, yeah.
I said it.
All right.
You hired Jay Stratton.
You hired Dr. Travis Taylor.
It sounds like maybe you guys are taking a part of flying saucer or building one and they kind
of joked about it.
Well, yeah, we kind of like to do that if we got a chance to.
Yeah, yeah.
You know, it's so compartmentalized with a company like that, the President even told
us, it's like, he has tons of projects going on that he is not read into because that's,
you know, that's how it's stovepipe.
So with this company out there and you and I going out there and getting people were
approaching us that were told to approach us.
And that was really interesting to me because I was having so much at that thing that there
were people in the audience, the people still don't know who they are.
And they trusted us with numerous things which will be coming public at some point.
Yeah.
Well, we went there with some goals and minds as if they goals and talking to Jay Stratton
and to Travis Taylor would have been if that was all we got that would be awesome.
We didn't know for sure if that was going to happen, but that's what we went there to
do.
And then we ended up meeting a bunch of other people who introduced themselves and began
a dialogue with us that I think we were bare fruit throughout this whole year.
And I was like, okay, you know, we're going to film this.
I got my buddy all the way from, you know, he flew in from Mexico and here we go.
And then I was like, oh, no, man, we're not recording in a hotel room.
I was like, oops, not about that.
You know, visually, but we had to do it kind of private.
We needed to make sure that it was the information was well documented.
Another thing that, so when we started the interview, something that Jay said kind of
right away, that was so interesting to me was that all sap from that very onset was
technological.
It was technology.
It was about discovery of disruptive technologies.
And you look at all the durs and the reports, and obviously they're thinking forward
looking 30, 50 years from now.
What could be a disruptive technology?
No matter where it's from, what could be a disruptive technology.
And then he said, but look, where the evidence led is that there were other things that
we learned.
There was a disruptive technology aim, but that there were a lot of other things they
learned when they were studying things like the ranch.
So that really threw me for a loop that, you know, something like, OASAP came in with
the idea of identifying future threats.
And then realized, wow, there's a lot more going on.
He talked about that in his interview with us.
So we spoke his off.
That's just this one.
Yeah.
Eyes off.
And of large or off.
I came with our own statement.
A.B.
Comment marker.
Okay.
Jay, you've done it on camera interview before.
Have you done interviews before?
So it's the first.
I mean, your world is the black world.
Last night's time.
Right?
Can you give me broad strokes of your career, the highlights, and I kind of secure a program
to your work now?
Sure.
You know, I started military.
I was a full-time reservist with the Air Force, and then I moved up to Maryland to work
at Pax River to do weapons integration with the F-18 flight test out of Navier.
And from there, I went to the Office of Naval Intelligence, where I was recruited to be an air
space engineer, working with them, to look at, you know, really apply the blue knowledge
as we call it, and apply it to the red, and potential adversaries, and right up, reports
on what I think foreign capabilities can do or not do, in a sense, reverse engineering.
Absolutely.
And take that into DIA, went over to the Defense Intelligence Agency, to work in the Defense
Warning Office, where I was applying the same knowledge, but at a higher level, and more
kind of orchestrating the intel community at that point.
And there's a term we use validation, whereas if you're building an F-22, or you're building
a joint strike fighter, you know, you're really kind of designing that to counter a potential
threat, and that potential threat needs to be a validated threat, because what we can't
have happen is a Lockheed Martin or Boeing, you know.