And I'm sure we'll talk about the task force,
but I had a five-year plan of how we're going to get
all of these things that we needed.
But if you're just a working group,
and trying to do your job and my hat,
and maybe at the headquarters,
I had a certain amount of wiggle room
for trying to get things done in authorities, right?
But you needed something above all that.
You needed something at that sick death level,
at that ODE and I level,
that could reach into everything
and had the authority to get the answers that needed.
And Lu and I knew we needed that.
And every time we would try to knock on a door
and say, hey, we need that, here's what we know, right?
Here's what we've seen.
A little bit of history on the offs app
and other things.
Yeah, you get the door kind of shutting your face
because it's back to that careerism.
I don't know.
This is not, I don't know.
I'm afraid of the Washington Post.
Was there any involvement of her these stories
from people we know about fundamentalist religious people,
high-ups who were concerned about its demons
or were messing with forces of biblical proportions?
There's absolutely some concern there.
And I did see it in writing one time in my career
where someone was asking me to push back
because they're religious concerns.
And you should wave off of this topic
because literally what they're telling me,
shouldn't be involved in this.
I know it exists.
I think what my professional opinion is
after again years and now of being involved
is that seems to have died off.
I think one, now I'm elevated into that senior level
and a lot of my colleagues that were all at the same level
that had grown up with me throughout the process,
we don't really think that way.
Right, so I think kind of the old guard was moving out,
the new guard was moving in.
And it never once after that early DIA stuff
did it ever, ever stop our getting away.
It was just early on when kind of that old guards there
and protecting their own, you know, what they believe.
December 2017 it blows up New York Times story.
I don't know if you knew that was coming,
but I know, you know, the blue has been through the rigor
since then.
I also know that Senator Reed, who, you know,
let me know it was coming.
He starts getting phone calls immediately
from former, his former colleagues in the Senate.
And they're asking, hey, what's the deal?
Does this program real?
How do I find out about it?
Is that when you get sort of pulled back in
and you start doing briefings or?
Well, so I was sitting in my office at the other,
non, you know, UFO related job.
And I get an email from my old boss.
There was a link to the New York Times story
and she said Merry Christmas, because I had no idea
that was coming at all.
And it was literally a holy crap, you know,
when you're reading that and you have some inside baseball
knowledge and, but they didn't have any security concerns.
You know, it was like, yeah, if I had security concerns,
I would have addressed it with the security concern.
I had the, you know, I can't believe we're saying all this
and New York Times, because of everything
that was involved, right?
But I didn't know it was coming.
It took me by surprise.
I had zero intent at that point of working the topic again
and they're just one of them out.
They could revack it.
It's exactly what happened.
Exactly what happened.
So my old boss, the sent me the email,
some time after that sent me a position
and said I should consider it.
And I did and I applied and I got that.
That was that promotion.
I was actually stepping back into office
and able to tell you this to do a different job.
But at that point, you know, your pilots have been taking
the Congress, the Senate Armed Service Committee
and all these folks had interest in the topic.
And my boss realizing, you know, she knew all along.
Hey, I got one guy that's got some history in this
and the trust to tackle it appropriately
and keep it professional and do all the things
that need to be done.
So she reached out and said, hey, I want you to take this over.
And she really wanted a joint program as a word she used
but you know, a joint effort built to tackle this problem
and get out ahead of it because of the,
now, it's the districts of the world, right?
The people that we want to take care of.
And I'll only say her name because she's come out herself
and with that, I took it, I had the authority.
We call it Dirlos, directly, liaison authority.
I had directly guys on authority across the entire government.
She empowered me with her, you know, her, her power to do that
to say just go for it.
And I wouldn't let anything stop me unless they threw me out, right?
So I started going through my own education and saying,
here's what I need.
And that came from the years of looking at this
and I knew I needed things like the FBI and the Coast Guard
and others for their title 18 authorities.
I needed folks of the right title, 50 authorities,
the folks of the right title, 10 authorities.
And to do this right and to get that level of respect
and get to those true answers,
you've got to have the right people involved, right?
So I went out like building business
and started knocking on doors and now thanks to my new rank,
I pretty much got doors open, right?
And previously, they would have might,
might would have opened the doors, but now the,
I assume this guy has to say, at that point,
you know, we had the gimbal and other things
right that people know about, but we had more, obviously.
I'm going through what we know, we don't know what we think
and everywhere I went because, again,
of that education of how to present the data,
how to present the information, they went, holy crap.
How can we help, right?
And I ended up with somebody in each organization,
it was kind of my belly button and say, hey,
this is your guy, he'll help you.
And I just started building out that business
and that framework and getting the things
that we needed to be successful.
I would call it at that point a partnership,
not a task force, because really,
you know, task force is a legal thing
and in the DOD circles, but we were this,
this partnership with the right people,
across the services, everybody approaching it
from the right perspective, that thing.
No, I started loosely calling it a task force,
but that was very loose, it was really,
and the way I would brief it as partnership,
you know, as I kind of show who's helping out.
And but at that point, I am brief and Congress,
you know, from that day forward, right?
Where I went in and briefed a couple of the committees
on my plan, I had what I called a one-pager.
Again, I'm, you know, from marketing perspective,
everything on one page, and here's what I'm gonna do,
and here's how I'm gonna do it, and they loved it,
and they got behind it, and you saw some language
coming out of the authorization for that.
I heard it became a hot ticket that, you know,
whereas before it was not nothing that ever popped up
in Congress and suddenly, hey, let's have a hearing,
show us the video.
Absolutely, and again, it's how you present the data, right?
And there were plenty, there were still a few
of the old guard kind of hanging out
that could prevent me from being successful,
and some of them did not want to hear from me, right?
They don't want to get the briefing,
but every time I finally got the brief,
they were supportive.
Every congressman, I ever briefed, except one,
I won't say who, and it gets back to the belief word.
Everybody understood where I was coming from,
and the problem said, and at the end of the day,
the business I built was working, and it was,
what we finally needed, right?
It's sort of reminds you of Michael Corleoni,
just what I'm out, that I thought I was out,
they pulled me back in, it's a kind of thing.
So, again, he was not a UFO guy, he was doing his job.
And each of the times he was asked to do this,
he was doing his job.
And you know, something else he said,
that really impacted me was, you know,
he was a really high rank, and I don't want to get into exactly
like how that works, but, you know,
we'd say in a equivalent of, let's just say, really high rank.
So, a lot of people could have pressured him
because of their rank to try to diminish the work he was doing,
but he resisted that all along the way,
and did the right thing, and I just,
I thought that was a really cool thing to hear from somebody,
and to know it to be true.
Yeah, the public knows a lot about the role of Lou Elisando,
both in blowing the story wide open,
and trying to get a bigger program,
and in bringing some of the aviators and other witnesses,
escorting them to Congress, he and Chris Melon,
work on pushing that ball down the field.
Jay Stratton is the unsung hero,
who is working in obscurity,
but doing the really important stuff,
and this was, he didn't have a program,
it wasn't called the UAP Task Force.
It was after that New York Times story,
and Congress starts asking questions
that he was putting in charge of an inquiry,
you know, to try to pull all the different strings together
to start pulling information together and cases,
and getting a structure of an organization
that became the UAP Task Force later on.
Jay Stratton started the UAP Task Force,
and that was huge for transparency on the subject.
I do wanna say you're like, he's the unsung hero.
I'm gonna say though, Lou gets a lot of grief
that it's not valid grief.
He's really endured a lot of slings and arrows, as you say.
So it's like, you know, be in a hero,
and this ain't what it cracked up to be, maybe.
I mean, he is to me, absolutely a hero to this topic,
and I think it's important what he's done.
I think Jay coming forward with us on camera.
I think I hope.