Spending tons of money against a threat that they say exists where the government needs
to say it exists.
So it's kind of a contractual thing of you're building to the validated threat and that's
what I did at the Defense Intelligence Agency.
Along with also having a science and technical intelligence hat with the Defense of
Warning Office to look across the spectrum at technology specifically air and space that
are leading edge things that could be disruptive and challenges in the future.
We're looking 10, 20, and sometimes 50 years out depending on the topic and trying to
provide the Department of Defense and across the Intel community a better understanding
of some of those potential disruptive threats so that we could get ahead of the game and
counter them.
When you're at DIA, I'm ignorant of this stuff, but you are Navy guy who then goes to work
for DIA.
Does that mean you're a Navy guy with DIA or you're always a Navy guy?
So when I transitioned to the Office of Naval Intelligence, I came to the service.
So I'm a Navy employee with the national and tell community.
So your service centers, the Office of Naval Intelligence, the nasic, national air and
space and tell center, the missile and space and tell center is a sub component of the
DIA that's here in Huntsville and then you have the NCIA, which is a Marine Corps intelligence
activity and then finally the National Ground Intel Center at Charlottesville.
Those are the four of what we call service centers and now you're going to have one for the
space force, co-located at right-pattest and air force space.
Those are service centers that support the analysis that supports the Navy or supports
the Marine Corps, supports the Army, but in reality they are all funded by the Director
of National Intelligence now, the ODI and I, as National Intel funded billets that are able
to support.
So people refer to the ODI, the Office of Naval Intelligence is the Navy's Intel Center.
The reality is it's the National Maritime Intel Center where we are the threat at the
maritime and when you think of Navy too, you got to remember that Navy is the Navy, but
the Navy also has an Air Force and the Navy has an Army and the Navy's Army has an Air
Force, right?
So it's a big service.
With that, when I have a big footprint and a big concern, but in all of that, the key in
bringing up that the ODI and I funds the four service centers is very important because
back to the threat that justifies the building of new systems and such, right?
The Air Force really wants a program.
They might go to an Asia and say, we need a threat to drive that program and we are funded
by the National side of the house, so we can say, well, we don't take orders from the Air
Force in that regard, we'll take orders from the Navy so we can, you know, this is the
assessment, right?
That's driven out of treecraft and that's the answer.
It's going to independent, you know?
It's a very independent, and a lot of people don't realize that, you know, they look
at those service Intel centers as kind of parts of the Air Force parts of the Army.
They are on paper, but in reality, you know, the majority of their budget comes from
the National.
So, you have high security clients, you sense it if you stop the sensitive as you get.
The author of my career, so from there, you know, do you want back to ODI to be the head
of Air Warfare?
Really?
That was the deputy initially, then the fleet it up was, we say, to be the director of Air
Warfare for ODI.
And when I first went back, we had everything that touches there in the Navy, so science
and technical side as well as the operational and tactics side, we call it spear is kind
of the nickname for the name that that organization uses.
We've got a history all the way back to Desert Storm.
If you watch Top Gun originally Charlie, that's briefing the Migs, she was based on a
spear analyst.
So, the group that I led has that kind of pedigree of talking about how capabilities operate.
So, you know, your National Intel Center, it nasic, for example, right, can talk about
a Russian fighter and you know, just throw an example when you, everybody knows we look
in Russia.
A Russian fighter talk about how fast it flies, how high it can fly based on it in their
assessments, right?
What spear does is we get into the head of the pilots, and we try to talk about how they're
going to fly that aircraft.
You know, when the analogies they've used for years is hockey players, right, every hockey
player has an out of skate, some of them are better than the others, but it's really about
the game, right?
It's about everything else but skating, skating comes second.
So if you think about that and apply it to a fighter aircraft, it's how they're, how
they're deploying that, right?
And guys, what my background can watch, somebody flying an airplane and go, man, he's
probably Russian, right?
You know, whoever, right, everybody, that's probably American, so, you know, you really
can recognize some of the techniques and the way they do things.
You know, if mutual friend of ours was trying to describe how high up you went and he
compared you to a two-star animal, that wasn't accurate exactly.
You weren't comfortable with that, but how would I explain to our audience how far up
the wrong you went?
I'm sure it's, it's right in, and I didn't want to really push any buttons with that.
So from, oh, and I went to the Pentagon and I worked in in two and six, which is the headquarters
level for naval intelligence.
The director of naval intelligence is, is dual-headed is what we call the in two and
six, was just the, you know, the op-nav office code.
At that point, I was still a 15, and then I went off to be the J2, the director of intelligence
for the joint warfare in health, the center of Dahlgren, and then from there I was promoted
initially to what we call tier one, defense intelligence senior level, tier one, which
is a, as a senior executive position, and then was, well, then eight months or so, I was
bumped up to a tier two, which is where the two-star comes in, you know, it's an equivalency
throughout my career, it's been, you know, are you really equal, right?
We always throw out GS-15s or kernels or, you know, there's an equivalency, but you don't
go bustling around the Pentagon saying, oh, how rank you, or, you know, so, right, yeah, but
you do have the, the gravitas, if that's a good word to use, that's not a good word to use,
the kind of the, the peer level, right?
So, you know, if I'd go into a meeting with a two-star or one-star, you know, kind of
have a peer level, so I'm not put in, in a corner, you know, and typically in my meetings,
I, you know, I was there representing someone higher than me, as well as, sometimes I'm
representing myself, but sometimes I'm there representing someone higher than me, so then I
inherit their authority, I'm sitting at their seat with their name on it, so I'm speaking
for that person, I wouldn't be interested in that meeting if I couldn't speak for that person,
and a lot of that in the Pentagon is resource sponsoring, so, you know, I said in many
tables where I was representing the resource sponsor, and that gets attention because acquisition
programs at your Navier, your NAVC, your Air Force material command, those are all built on requirements
back to the thread, right? And, and those requirements are paid for by resource sponsors,
so the resource sponsor says, we need a new jammer, and, and from that resource sponsor,
requirements are driven, and then capabilities are built, and they go to whoever can build that
capability, whether that's Navier or that's Nav, you know, whoever that might be, right? So,
so in those circles, you know, you get to know a lot of people, and that helped me later to really
kind of know who I need to reach out to. Can you describe for me at what point UFOs they were called
then, UFOs now, at what point that kind of got on your radar screen, was there something that you had
at least a casual interest in growing up, or it came a point in your professional career
that it landed on your desk? Yeah, every time I've done anything related to UAP or UFO has been my
job. And, and what I mean by that, I didn't really have a passion growing up, I didn't have
all the books, I didn't watch all the TV shows, I stepped into a job, I had the Defense Intelligence
Agency, where some things came across the desk, again, thinking technologies and other things,
where I needed to really kind of dig in and understand potentials, and those potentials,
you know, I kept an open mind, a skeptic mind, whatever you want to call it, you know, looking for
something that can answer this, and all the means that I had to chase that, but there were definitely
some times where we really couldn't close the loop. And with that, we realized that something needed
to be done about it. We should maybe just fill in our listeners about Hal J. Stratton ended up
studying UFOs and related mysteries, because he made it clear to us in our conversation with him.
He's not a UFO guy. He's not sitting at home watching UFO videos on YouTube. He'd watch
guitar playing videos on YouTube, but not UFOs. He didn't have a whole bunch of books. He didn't have
an biting interest in it, but he ended up moving from Office of the Naval Intelligence over to
DIA, and it became an acquaintance and colleague of Dr. Jim LaCascie, who was the creator of
eventually became the creator of the OSAP program. What became OSAP, and LaCascie had an interest
in in Skinwalker Ranch, in the book that Callum and I, Callum Keller, heard I wrote. And while
we'll let Jay Stratton explain how that process went. I can remember telling our mutual friend,
Dr. LaCascie, right, that some of this stuff, I don't, and I hate saying the word now,
because I have so much more background, but the word believe, right? The belief isn't there,
necessarily, that I'm seeing what I think, or was being reported, right? So that evolution between
2006, and then to 2008, at that time, I had to go to Iraq, just normal deployment, and because we did
to place civilians. A lot of people don't realize that civilians are just on the hope, just like military.
In 2006 and 7th time for him, as we were trying to think about this problem said, Jim LaCascie says,