Basically, I made the comments on the effect of,
I'd love to see one with my own eyes.
And one I meant by one is a nuts and bolts craft, right?
Because in my mind, that's why I'm a technology aerospace guy.
I'm thinking the craft that I can go touch and put my hands on, right?
Or I'd like to see one of these things in person.
And I'm just getting ready to go.
And Jim was always tracking the ranch.
And he kind of made a joke.
I don't even see it's a joke.
A comment of, hey, there's one place in the world.
We might see one of these things as this place.
And he hands me your book.
And I throw the book in my backpack and literally
took it to a rack with me.
So I read that book in the green zone and in my downtime.
And before I even got back, we're talking
and things are proceeding along.
But so I come back.
And at that time, we were initially,
the defense warning office in the IA was at the die act we
called the Defense Intelligence Analysis Center
at Bowling Air Force Base.
Now, granted, I was flight test back in the day
as Pax River and Naval Air Station,
which is in St. Mary's County, Maryland.
So I still live there.
And I never sold my house throughout this whole process
because I liked where I lived.
But I was making really terrible commutes.
So I agreed to work at the Defense Intelligence Agency
and made that commute.
And then the process they transferred us,
14 miles through the city to another place.
And I can remember the quote to this day.
There's also only 14 miles J,
but it's 14 miles of DC hell, right?
You're going through the commute there.
So anyway, we end up in this place.
It's called Clarenod.
And it was really killing me physically.
You know, just to drive every day and the stress of that.
I love the job, but the stress of getting there in home.
And in 2008, oh, when I offered me the position
to come back and be the Deputy Director of Warfare,
which was a lot better commute.
And I love the one I, I kind of grew up there
and in the Intel community.
So I took that job and left.
Dr. Ocaschi stayed in touch.
But that contract, it was already in the beginnings.
And then in 2009, if I remember my time-longing rate,
he put it on Fed Bizzops to be bid.
And they had two bidders that I remember.
I won't be in Bob Bigel, Bigel of Airspace
and other being a company that I don't remember the name of,
but it was a company that did a lot of business
with DIA and kind of that contract rolled.
You know, you have your favorite customers
in your favorite.
But there were more than one bid.
I didn't know what funny business that you can see.
It was none at all.
It was.
And I know all of the leadership, right?
I worked there, worked for them.
They're the most straightforward honest people
that you can imagine.
And they could not, I could never in a million years
imagine them taking any kind of favoritism
in their account.
I guarantee they went over everything very detail
and made a decision based on the best response
to the proposal that they had.
They fire up this program, Bigel of Airspace
and Springs in Action, they create these 38 papers.
We've heard that described as junk science.
Do you recall how those papers were received
when they came out?
So what I remember, so LaCatski, Dr. LaCatski,
that was driving that and our colleague, Dr. Howe put off,
kind of led the charge there, supporting Bigel of Airspace.
And the idea of them in my mind was awesome, right?
I'll have this reference document
that I can always go back to on all these different technologies.
They did come back being really academic, right?
Very high level, academic, whereas we're dealing
with the defense intelligence agency that the predominance
is the liberal arts degree.
And there were on terrorism, was hot and heavy,
right, we're hiring people who are experts in that culture
and hiring some people just because they
speak Arabic, and all these things, it wasn't.
We weren't hiring the best and brightest engineers
at the time because it just wasn't the need
to do the DIA.
So if you take all of that into context and you realize
your average GIA analyst is going to look at that
with their polysci or history background and go,
what is this, right?
Whereas other folks out AFRL and folks with the educational background
and look at it and go, oh, this is interesting.
But they may say some of it is junk science
because it is bleeding edge and that's what we wanted.
We wanted to know what they thought
is the leading expert on a potential technology,
what would be pushing the edge of that envelope
because I needed something to point back to
if I saw something in any kind of reporting
and I could say, look, based on Dr. XYZ,
that wrote this report, that's significant.
You've seen what else was produced by a set
of that 27 months, I mean, it's a lot of stuff.
But a lot of it is some of it is pretty weird.
I mean, the skinlock, right?
I've heard it said now, people who wanted to integrate
the program that it was nonsense.
It got off and all this weird paranormal stuff.
I was never what it was supposed to be.
And it was a waste of money.
And that's why it was canceled because it got
into these weird topics that are just too far out.
In general, can you address the work that was done
by all that?
The reports that you've read that haven't made public
were those worthwhile on it?
So I think, so I'm back at O and I at this point, right?
So my day-to-day interaction with the contract
and with bass was not there.
I didn't have that day-to-day.
However, Dr. LeCatsky and I, again,
he wants to pick my brain on things that are being seen.
And I'm still in a role where I'm concerned
about threats to aviation and those types of things, right?
So it's good to keep me and the team that I had
and my larger role-to-decks of experts across the Intel community.
So it was good to keep me up to speed.
The heart and soul of O sap was those technology areas
and the heart and soul of those technology areas
of preventing a disruptive technology.
The other stuff that came out of that was collateral.
You know, if you go to the ranch to see
a nuts and bolts craft that you might be able to put your hands on
and you see other things that you can't explain,
no one to this day can explain.
Is it something to do with the technology?
Is it an effect on the body?
Is it something that's driving you to see things
that aren't really there?
You know, all those things needed to be studied.
And again, throughout this whole process, I'm learning.
All of this comes into the forefront later
with the bigger task force and knowing what I needed
and knowing the kinds of expertise that I needed
and that true diversity may not mean,
whether you're from a certain country
or you're, I think background or anything else.
Or true diversity, maybe just
clearly the way you think based on your own background
that is kind of an asymmetric approach
to the technology area, right?
For example, hiring biologists to look at the terrorist network
and the thread that of radical Islam
and how it spreads like a virus, right?
You take that same mindset to other things
and the various phenomena that we're seeing.
It's important to bring in that kind of diversity
just as it's just purely the way they think.
And I always like to bring in folks
with that kind of background that didn't have a military background
because now they're not in this box
and this viewpoint that they're always trying to mold things
into, they're coming at you with, well,
have you thought about this, right?
And that is where the true power of those,
and those papers come from too
because then you've got to be something to point back to you
to say, hey, take a look at this, what do you think, right?
To another academic or, and how could you see that applied?
The family that vacations together, stays together.
At least that was the plan.
It accepts now the dester Lee Desklerk is saying,
he can't confirm your connecting rooms.
Wait, what?
That's right, ma'am, you have rooms 201 and 709.
No, we cannot be five floors away from our kids.
The doors of double locks will be fine.
When you want connecting rooms confirmed before you arrive,
it matters where you stay.
Welcome to Hilton.
I see your connecting rooms are already confirmed.
Hilton, for this day.
Okay, Chad, today you're going to drive the all-electric Toyota BZ.
But my electric vehicle, phobia.
I'm not ready, Dr. Ross.
I believe in you.
Oh my gosh, we're inside it.
Try to take deep breaths, okay?
Move the ventilated seats, they're touching me!
We can do this, Chad.
Drive the car, how do you feel, Chad?
I feel...
Kurt!
Woohoo!
I'm doing it!
The all-electric BZ, one drive can change your mind.
Toyota, let's go places.
So Jay Stratton is not a UFO guy.
He's, I don't know if you say, a career intelligence officer,
but oh and I, to DIA,
that the UFO thing hits at him and he realizes there's a void
there. We need to do this, right?
There are potential threats.
We don't know where they're coming from.
So I'm going to create the UAP Task Force
and we're going to look at this in a badass way.
And we're going to be clear with the American public.
He also made sure to put that in.
We're going to be clear with the American public.
He did that for a while and then he had a break, right?
From, it wasn't his job.
And during the time he was doing intelligence in another field,
are we up to that point in the story?
So the public, the UFO public, is aware of the programs
that Jay Stratton was involved in.
We've mentioned the names of those.
What they don't know is there are already familiar with some of his work.
For example,