P is treated differently because man, he's done great things and now the public is going to
learn about them.
Well you remember, end of 2020, Congress says we want to program, in fact we want to report.
You got, here's the legislation.
We want that report.
You got six months to write it.
So January, Jay's organization starts working on it.
The UAP Task Force, we're going to put this report together and it's precisely that moment.
He gets he ain't got it.
And it looked really suspicious.
I remember, I reported on it exactly the time when you need him most when the most experienced
guy in the U.S. government on the UFO mystery is taken out of it and given another job.
But he actually was supposed to be doing that job all along.
This was a temporary duty.
So he has taken out the people who he had left there.
They didn't have a full-time position.
They didn't have any full-time positions.
They didn't have a budget here.
Put this report together for Congress and I think they did a remarkable job in six months
to get together.
That's right.
And he had two people that were putting this report together and I do agree it was a phenomenal
job.
He even talked about why, in the interviews with us, he even talked about why he started
in 2004, rather than going back all the way through UFO history, I was like, why did you
start in 2004?
And he explains that really well and there's a clip of it.
So you get a lot of, you know, I said on numerous occasions, right?
Trust is important.
And you know, I think it was Colin Powell that said you can't search trust.
The minute you're, I mean, we're already 70 years behind the power curve for trust, right?
Because everybody says the government's lying to us, right?
And the whole blue book thing and the whole Roswell thing killed, killed trust, right?
Very good reason why not to even go there, right?
And then this whole discussion, you know, the task force and everything else, we kind of started
in 2004, right, is Mr. Bracet and the congressional hearings.
You got to start somewhere and it might recommendation when I created it, is that that
2004 start data is important because that was the first case in recent history where I had
pilot reporting and data, right, back to the data.
But you take all of that trust and then you get this bureaucratic machine that is the
Department of Defense and the intel community.
And then, you know, this is an inner agency, a whole government.
So now you're talking about Congress and you're talking about all the other departments,
your DHS is in your transportation, right, with FAA and everybody has like, you've got to
have a singular message and that's why I wanted the task force to have its own spokesperson
so that we're briefing as much as we can of what we're dealing with.
But so you get this whole machine and no matter how hard you try, email is not the best
communication method, right, and hardly anybody picks up the phone these days.
So what would happen to me is I would see a response from the DUD spokesperson that, and
I would say, oh my gosh, why did we say that, right, you come back and you try to clean
up, but there's no cleaning up at that point.
So it was all that circular and then you had agendas, right, you still had, I think you're
probably aware of Luz's previous and, you know, you had that happening.
And that was also manipulating and driving, because again, DUD is very ranked conscious
ranked structured organization, right.
So if someone's senior is telling you to do something, it's not illegal, they're probably,
you know, don't want to risk things and go with it.
So I think you had some of that go on.
Now I'll tell you, even as they had the task force, I didn't, I didn't get into those
politics on purpose.
In fact, I went back to my old days.
The fence intelligence agency when I was saying, you were nationally funded and I need to
make an assessment that isn't manipulated by politics, which is actually the law now,
following 9 and 11.
I stuck to my guns that I, I am here to, you know, working on behalf of the Intel community
to give American people an answer and numerous occasions.
Anytime someone tried to play the ranked game, I would just stick to my guns.
Essentially, the idea that he would choose a date where they have a great amount of systems
data and move forward from there, it makes total sense.
And I think that was a very smart move.
I'm sure there is historic data that we can look at now, but I think that was a great
starting point.
So that was very cool when he did that.
And the two people that he tasked with doing that report, again, did a remarkable job.
There's something else he did that you and I have referenced in various reports without
attributing it to him in any way, because it couldn't use his name.
But there was a briefing presentation that was put together.
And it was an accumulation of all these cases that Jay and his colleagues had been investigating.
And a lot of them were had included video and photos and things of that sort.
And he put this together as a briefing presentation for higher ups in the Pentagon, for members
of Congress, for defense contractors and for the intelligence community.
And he made the case, hey, this is real.
This is a genuine unknown.
This is a national security matter.
We need to take a look at it.
I understand it's a very persuasive piece of information, but some of the images that were
in that briefing document.
It's classified, but some of the images that came from that are not classified.
Right.
I mean, we'll be clear because we've been clear all along the way is as journalists
obtaining and releasing unclassified information is absolutely fine.
No designation, nothing like that.
Sure, something could be contained within something classified.
I don't know what I know for sure is that it was confirmed by the Pentagon.
That stuff that we ended up releasing, especially regarding the 2019 events on the West
Coast, which is something we've covered on an episode at length, one of our last episodes.
And I think that the key thing here that I think people should know is that you've got
this audio, visual presentation that is being shared within multiple intelligence agencies
why the reason why appears to be to destigmatize, to acclimate people to the possibility
of how do you report this and to encourage reporting going right back up the chain of
command where it should go, which is a smooth and cool process.
Prom was they didn't respond a lot to people when they were reported up and they realized
that was an error and that they should give feedback so people know these reports are going
somewhere.
We're taking them seriously.
He also needed to find a way to get beyond NDAs, because sometimes you just overclassify
stuff and people have to do an NDA because something was seen or picked up and they have
to go to the process of getting past NDAs, which I don't know he ever got, but I think
that's important moving forward for, you know, for error if it's going to do some great
work.
Yeah, a lot of those cases that were part of his briefing presentation ended up as part
of the UAP Task Force Report to Congress.
They didn't spell it out and any instances, but we know that that is the case and that
the Congress did respond and did take it seriously.
Jay Stratton left government in 2021 and entered the private sector.
He was happy to move to Huntsville, Alabama, to work for radians.
He was happy to bring Travis Taylor along and as we know, you know, we've been able to
share at least a couple of excerpts from this interview that we did.
There's a lot more coming from Jay Stratton, I think, in 2023.
Oh, I know.
Yeah, we know.
I mean, he is making it a point to communicate as clearly as possible with the American
public about his roles, what he did, what he hopes for the future with this, what's
currently going on.
I think it's great that people will be seeing a lot of him that he'll be coming and
talking about his roles and experiences.
I think when you can put a face, you know what I mean to these people that were really
before the unsung heroes.
I mean, Intel community people are deep inside.
They don't want to be in front of a camera, but now that people come forward a little
bit and give other people the encouragement and the permission, I think that that's
very powerful for witnesses that have been part of UFO exploitation and reverse engineering
programs and legacy programs or current programs to come forward through the new legislation
that has been passed into law, the protects whistleblowers.
And in fact, it's not just a right to come forward.
In fact, it's a duty.
If there have been programs that have been hidden from congressional oversight, proper
congressional oversight, you have a legal duty to come forward.
So I really hope people are encouraged by this in these programs that we do know exist,
that they do come forward and that they share with our Senate Intelligence Committee or
whatever the process is at this point to get this information for, then hopefully out
to American public, this technology is important, man.
A totally great, you know, I want to say this also about J. Stratton, although I've been
allowed to know of him and then to know him, he is not a source.
He did not leak any of these images to us.
This is a guy who plays by the rules.
It drove me crazy to know a guy like that who could answer these questions and who could
has access to all kinds of materials that I have not seen that you haven't seen, that
the public hasn't seen, but he played by the rules.
He used a stickler about that.
Now that he's in the private sector and he is a public citizen of private citizen, he has
a lot more flexibility to pursue these subjects.
He's definitely hooked on it now.
If he wasn't before, he is now.
And we're going to hear a lot more from him in 2023, but I just want to make it clear.
He's not a leaker.
He didn't leak any stuff to us.
It's so funny, man.
People are going to try to, I would too try to guess how this way.
Everybody's been wrong.
Everybody's been wrong about how information gets to journalists.
We don't need to...