You know, constantly telling, we would never have a source on.
But the thing is, is like, what does it mean to be a source?
Sometimes, you and I have received stuff
that we don't know exactly who or where came from.
So our job for years sometimes,
which is what's now a lot of that's coming out.
But like, for years, it's to figure out the validity
of information rather than the source of information.
That's interesting, isn't that?
That's something unexpected to me.
You know, the people who are real heroes in this saga,
this ongoing saga, Dr. James LaCatsky,
who's single, almost single, handedly,
with the help of Harry Reid and Robert Bigel
had got the ASAP program created.
And then Lu Elazando, who rescued the remnants of it
and got a tip and kept it going.
And then Jay, Stratton, who was part of all of this,
all those programs and beyond into the current era,
he might be the most important UFO government UFO
investigator ever of all of them.
And it's so great to be able to talk to him.
We have so much more that we haven't been able to share yet,
but we will, over the next course of the year,
and hopefully he'll be here to live sometime.
Yeah, and look, this program,
however, this audio and visual program,
it's because we know we can now.
Now we're gonna have people here.
It's every time we're able to use this
to get stuff out that you and I wouldn't normally be able
to get out in any traditional means.
So I am excited.
It would be great right here if there was somebody
who worked in one of the government UFO programs
that could sit right here next to us.
Wouldn't that be great?
Well, look at the wheels that are turning
because of the work of the guys I just mentioned.
Like Hatsky, Colom Calahir, Lu Elazando, Jay Stratton,
the work that they did,
toiling an obscurity for so many years,
is really paying dividends.
I mean, this is not a terrific report,
but the fact that it exists at all is amazing.
The fact that they have now have a streamlined process
and have taken away some of the stigma attached
to reporting UFOs is amazing progress
in a short period of time.
And Congress maintaining an ongoing interest in this.
They're demanding more information.
We don't know what's in the classified version of this,
but it's exciting.
It's awesome, and the legislation
that offers protection to whistleblowers
is also very exciting,
that we're gonna be exploring over the next nine, 10 months.
Is this George Nap being optimistic about that?
Let me take that back.
Let me take it back.
Then you can't think of that.
I heard it loud and clear,
it sounded like George Nap is being optimistic about.
You have our transparency in some way.
Look, man, we're only gonna get as far as we push it.
Nobody wants to give up information.
You know, if it's special to them,
there's no reason to, but I think if the public demands it,
we ask nicely and shake the doors a little bit.
Look, there are great people within our,
the majority of our armed services, our intelligence agencies.
You know, they are just like us.
They're curious about this, they're excited about it.
If it's not a matter of national security,
this is stuff that should be told to the American public.
So I am very optimistic by nature,
but it was kind of cool to hear some optimism from you.
You're not so optimistic sometimes when it comes to traveling
because of your curse.
And I wanna finish this trip and remind you what happened.
So we are, we do these great interviews
and we're just stoked, man, it was really fun.
We met really interesting folks that we ended up
having friendships with along the way
who I'm sure you will hear from in the future
who are involved in this topic, deeply.
So we're like, okay, let's just get home.
And of course, we're on some horrible airline.
There's this photo I put up on social media.
We look like Gorilla's man, we're, we have our bags
and we're just walking down this runway
just trying to get on this plane.
We're all messed up because guess what?
Turns out Miles, if COVID didn't kill you,
I was gonna kill you.
My buddy who we were with all week
had really bad COVID.
I'm like bleeding coughs and I was like, oh man,
you and I, we escaped it.
We thought we escaped.
There we are in the plane.
And then we get this lightning storm.
I have never seen so much lightning in my life out of window.
It was like, it just felt like doom
because of your travel curse.
But we got back and we still had to sit on this story
for, we had to sit on the story up until now
and a lot of times.
So it was, it's funny, as a journalist,
you've probably dealt with this tons,
but you gotta really respect that someone gives you their trust
and they're allowing you to do this.
So you gotta time everything right.
You can't just throw something up on YouTube
or throw something out on Twitter.
You have to do it responsibly.
Check everything before you do it.
And God forbid you make a mistake,
but if you do, you say it, right?
So that was kind of a neat trip.
We get back and man, we were tired, but we got what we needed.
Yeah, we got so much material from Dr. Taylor
and from Jerry Stratton and the folks at Radiance
and then the people, other people,
we met at the SCU conference.
And we were really excited to go ahead and share it
with the public, but it takes time, you know?
We didn't have the OK to go ahead
and spill all those beans.
We do now.
We have permission from Jay to use some parts of that interview
and I think we're probably gonna be using more
in the future and hopefully we'll be hearing from him live,
maybe on the stage and maybe on other stages.
This episode is brought to you by Nature's Bounty.
Nature's Bounty believes your body is brilliant,
naturally designed to thrive, inside and out.
For those always looking for new ways
to support your health from head to heels,
Nature's Bounty has a range of over 400 vitamins and supplements
born from 50 years of trust and care.
Nature's Bounty, it's in your nature.
Visit naturesbounty.com to learn more.
OK, so what's the big picture now?
Like as we do these and we try to put these pieces together
for public consumption.
And here we are in 2023, you know, what's the big picture man?
Where are we going with this from reports to error
to other agencies we know that are interested
in the UFO subject, like where are we going with this man?
Well, we know that because of that legislation,
there are whistleblowers who are lined up,
at least a few of them that we know of,
who are lined up prepared to tell what they know.
The most interesting, unanswered question is where are the goodies?
Is there met a materials stashed in a warehouse?
Are there intact craft as Bob Lazarus suggested somewhere
out in the desert?
Are there bodies?
You know, there are people who have told us
that they know that those things are true,
that there are materials, exotic materials from somewhere else.
The question is, are they going to be allowed to speak?
Now, I did express a little bit of optimism
a couple of minutes ago, but I think for them,
it's still a dicey deal, you know?
Stepping forward to tell these incredibly sensitive secrets
comes with the risk.
And we know that there are at least some of them
who are already facing potential consequences
for agreeing to step forward.
Hopefully the stories will come out.
The information will be conveyed to Congress,
whether or not that information gets to us,
the public, that's another matter,
but we'll be doing our best to get it out.
The process designed through the whisperer protection stuff,
the idea of using something like the Inspector General
to move forward with complaints of reprisal
and this sort of thing, I think it is fair to say
because we've said before, that process,
whether or not it has been formalized,
there are people in this subject
who are using the right mechanisms
to get the information where it needs to go
at a fear of reprisal.
That is something current, that is happening.
So I'm encouraged that that process is there
to protect people, ultimate goal, let's just say it like it is.
There are UFO study programs in multiple agencies
across every branch of our military,
many of which we know about the idea is,
can they go through a formal process
to bring those illegal programs to where they should go?
This shouldn't be a job of journalism,
this should be a job of cleaning house,
this should be something that they do on the inside.
Journals do what they do, this should be clear and straightforward.
If there are unknown illegal programs dealing
with non-terrestrial technologies, yes,
that's a huge issue for humanity,
but this also needs to be fixed on the inside.
Absolutely, and this report, for example,
there's a line in there that I found pretty interesting.
It says that we have no evidence of any direct human health
consequences of exposure to UFOs.
I can hope that sometime in the next 12 months
that the arrow folks will go down the hall
and knock on the door at the DIA
and ask to see the OSAP files, because OSAP, as we have reported,
has very definitive evidence about harmful consequences
from people who got too close to UFOs.
And there are some very dramatic and well-documented cases
that the DIA program followed for a number of years.
So having seen some of these reports,
the thing you're saying is that arrow,
who's studying the UFO phenomenon,
they should already have all this documentation
of a huge program like OSAP that clearly shows
that there have been health issues that have been caused
directly from close proximity to UAP.
And they don't seem to have any knowledge of that.
It was similar to the two guys who appeared
before they're congressional hearing.
The first congressional hearing of 54 years
when they were asked about nuclear incidents, incidents
or a nuclear missile.